[ Music ]
>> Good morning.
Welcome to our --
Thank you.
It's great to be here.
Thanks everybody for coming.
Welcome to our session on
inducing Podcast Analytics.
I'm James Boggs I manage the
business team for Apple Podcasts
and Siri Auto Briefs.
And we've got a great session
planned for you today.
First, I'm going to share some
details of our podcast business
over the last year, including
some very interesting and
exciting milestones.
Then I'm going to welcome Anne
Wootten from our engineering
team to the stage, and she's
going to take us through some
updates to Podcast app for iOS
12.
After Anne, Alec Reitter will
take us through a demo of
Podcast Analytics.
And then, we will finish up with
Anne sharing some requirements
and taking a look at resources
available to podcast makers.
First off, an update on our
podcast business.
Well, we're just shy of the 13th
anniversary of the launch of
iTunes 4.9.
That's the moment when we took
podcast mainstream for the first
time.
And podcasts have come a long
way since then.
Our constant catalog has never
been more entertaining,
inspiring and educational.
And we've never reached more
listeners around the world than
we do right now.
We're reaching them with some
great programming like "Sandra"
from Gimlet.
This is a brand-new program from
one of the leading independent
podcast networks out of New
York.
And it stars really big talent
Kristen Wiig, Alia Shawkat and
Ethan Hawke.
It's a really fun, scripted
comedy drama about the inner
workings and quirks of a virtual
assistant.
Los Angeles-based Wondery, is
one of the venture capital
backed network startups working
in podcast today.
And last year, Wondery
collaborated with "The LA Times"
to produce the thrilling true
crime story of a charming but
sociopathic con man, Dirty John.
The Hollywood style production
values, powerful investigative
journalism and remarkable
storytelling, which is just
riveting.
It drove this show to the top of
the charts in the US, several
other markets around the world.
If you haven't had a chance to
check it out, I recommend it.
It's a great binge.
And of course, podcast fans
everywhere are thrilled and
enjoying "Oprah's Super Soul
Conversations."
This is the audio installment of
the queen of talk's iconic
interview franchise.
And we are overjoyed to have
Oprah on Apple Podcast.
These examples are just three of
the more than 550,000 shows
available today on Apple
Podcasts.
That's quite a bit more content
to listen to than the original
3,000 programs we launched with
back in 2005.
We're continually refreshing and
managing our directory.
Automatically retiring shows
which become technically
unavailable, or those that run
afoul of our directory content
guidelines.
Such as those with spammy
content or shows seeking to
manipulate our top charts.
Don't do that.
Just, please don't do that.
At the same time as we're
managing the directory, we're
accepting thousands of new
submissions per week.
That way, our catalog is
continually refreshed and our
users around the world can
always find something great to
listen to.
Amongst those more than 550,000
active shows, we have over 18.5
million episodes of content.
That's more than 8 million hours
of programming.
So, you better start listening,
you better start binging.
As a reminder Apple Podcasts is
available in 155 countries.
That's not only for the
distribution of existing shows,
but for the submission and
acceptance of new programming
from each one of those markets.
The podcast directory serves an
audience in all 155 of those
countries with content in more
than 100 languages.
So, that means if you're a
Korean native speaker, ex-pat
living in Toronto, you can find
some great audio programming
from home right in Apple
Podcasts.
And we're particularly proud of
this.
Particularly proud to have such
a diverse catalog and be one of
the easiest ways to reach a
global audience for audio
programming that there is.
The data from our beta version
of Podcast Analytics shows some
remarkable listener affinity and
engagement.
We looked at several hundred of
our recent top episodes, those
with more than seven days of
playback data, and we found some
really notable average
consumption.
Of courses, data is anonymized
and aggregated and a sample.
So, no personally identifiable
information is included and it's
not a comprehensive statistic,
but interesting nonetheless.
It shows that once an episode is
started, on average about 80% of
that episode content was
consumed.
This is great stuff.
And a real testament to the
affinity and engagement the
podcast audience has with this
high-quality content.
Last fall, we successfully
integrated more than 50,000
iTunes U collections into Apple
Podcast.
This is content from some of the
world's best educational
institutions; including
developing iOS 11 apps with
Swift from Stanford's Paul
Hegarty.
Naturally, we're eager for the
new installment of this class
series later this year.
As part of Apple Podcast,
teachers can now leverage the
episode serial ordering support
in podcast app.
They can reach new, broader
audience of life-long learners
around the world.
And they can distribute their
content on tvOS for the first
time.
We're seeing some great use of
modern podcast tags, which we
introduced last year, right here
on stage at WWDC.
Many podcasts includes trailers
to thematically introduce the
feel and sound of their show.
This is the best way really to
launch a new podcast.
And ESPN for example, makes
great use of trailers.
And in addition is amongst the
chart-topping shows that uses
seasons and bonus content.
This allows Jody Avirgan and the
team to easily present the
thematically different
collections of episodes in each
season.
In addition to seasons and bonus
content, "30 for 30" feeds their
super fans with bonus episodes.
These complement the full season
episodes.
A best practice regarding bonus
content is to make sure that
your bonus episodes are tagged
appropriately to the full season
episodes.
This will ensure proper ordering
of the content in Apple Podcast.
And of course, episode number.
We're using this handy reference
for your audience inside podcast
app.
We're also making use of episode
numbers that you provide in the
RSS feed in Podcast Analytics.
An innovative crop of
venture-backed hosting startups
have started to grow.
Organizations such as Anchor,
with some great new iOS based
creation tools ART19, which is
an easy to use solution for your
enterprise podcast needs.
And Simplecast with brand new
migration tools and a 2.0
version they just launched.
These next generation mobile
optimized podcast creation tools
can help make your programming
available to the world.
And these folks join our lineup
of longstanding hosting partners
from around the world including
Lipson, Megaphone, Omni Studios
and Wushka from Australia,
Spreaker, and more.
Check out our resources now for
our full list of Apple Podcast
hosting partners, HomePod, which
arrives soon in Canada, France
and Germany is an awesome
podcast machine.
Siri has been optimized for
podcast playback.
So, you can just ask Siri to
subscribe to or play your
favorite show.
We also offer audio news briefs.
Just ask Siri to play me the
news.
We're proud to be distributing
headline news bulletins from
some of the best news
organizations in the world
including NPR, the BBC, ABC
Australia, ESPN, Bloomberg, and
more.
You can ask Siri for audio
briefs in general news, sports,
business, and even get an update
on the goings-on in music from
our own Apple music team.
We're thrilled to celebrate the
incredible milestone of 50
billion episode downloads and
streams on Apple Podcast, since
the launch of the service in
2005.
With over 10.5 billion episode
downloads and streaming plays in
2016, and more than 13.7 billion
last year.
The growth trajectory of the
platform is amazing.
We're also thrilled that the
shows that are driving all this
consumption are of such a high
quality.
And it's a pleasure for us to be
able to champion this content on
top of our platform.
We celebrate the podcasts that
contribute to this 50-billion
milestone in one show in
particular, "Stuff You Should
Know" from Atlanta's How Stuff
Works Network.
The first podcast, and Apple
Podcast to exceed 500 million
downloads and streams.
Wow. Congratulations to Chuck,
Josh, Jerry and the rest of the
team.
Well done.
We're looking forward to the
next half-billion downloads and
streams.
So, with that business update,
let me welcome Anne to the stage
to take us through our app.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, James.
Thanks, James, and hi.
I'm Anne, and I run Podcasts
Engineering at Apple.
Before we dive much deeper into
analytics, I want to highlight a
few of the latest updates to the
podcast app.
As you probably heard in
yesterday's keynote, we are
thrilled to be launching
podcasts for Apple Watch this
fall.
It was one of the most requested
features for Apple Watch and for
good reason.
Between HomePod and Apple Watch,
listening to podcasts has never
been easier or more hands-free.
We're also really excited to
share that we've enhanced our
support for chapters in the
podcast app.
In the upcoming iOS release,
we're extending full chapter
support to MP3s.
In addition to enabling
podcasters to segment their
episodes into shorter discrete
chapters, this functionality
also includes chapter art that
displays as the play head
advances across chapters.
So, podcasters can supplement
their audio with visual content.
In the upcoming iOS release,
we're also offering an improved
experience for podcast
notifications.
The new podcast notifications
are groups across shows and
episodes, into a single
expandable stack.
That reduces clutter on the
screen.
And we've also provided one-tap
access to notification settings
for all of your shows.
That means if you only want to
get notifications for your
favorite show, "99% Invisible,"
it's as simple as toggling the
switches on this single settings
page.
So, last year at WWDC, we
announced that Apple would be
launching Podcast Analytics for
the first time.
We were super excited to launch
at the end of 2017.
And Podcast Analytics is
available in beta right now,
today, to anyone with a podcast
in our catalog.
We know that this is a service
that was long desired and speaks
to a critical need in the
industry, as evidenced by work
like the remote audio data speck
being spearheaded by NPR.
So, it's important to us that we
provide this anonymous data back
to publishers to help them
better understand how their
audiences are consuming their
audio.
And all of the data and
analytics is based on the use of
the updated Apple Podcast App
from iOS 11 and iTunes 12.7.
We're collecting data only from
those operating systems,
forward.
And the analytics dashboard
includes listening data from
HomePod, AppleTV and will
include Apple Watch listening
data starting in watchOS 5.
As you know, privacy is really
important to Apple and we are
only showing aggregate data of
those users who have agreed to
use the Podcast App.
It is anonymous.
Not personally identifiable.
Not tied to your Apple ID.
And we only reflect data points
in aggregate that we've
collected from at least five
unique devices.
And it couldn't be easier to get
started.
You don't need to write any
code.
You don't need to use an SDK and
it's totally free.
If you have a podcast, all you
have to do is submit your feed
to Podcast Connect after you
signed in.
Get it approved, get some
listeners, then check your
performance through the Podcast
Analytics Dashboard.
Analytics reports data from
unique devices that engage with
the Podcast App.
As my colleague Alec is about to
show us from the Analytics
Dashboard, publishes can access
an overview that includes tables
and charts with data like unique
device counts for a selected
period of time.
Total time listened.
Time per device.
Average consumption.
Top countries, and more.
So, some of you may be familiar
with our podcast, "The Very
Hungry Tourists."
They're back for season two and
they even have some new cover
art.
Alec is going to take you on a
deeper dive of how to get the
most out of Analytics.
We're excited to continue
providing key listening metrics
for this industry and we are
listening to your feedback and
continuing to improve the
service.
So, thank you.
And with, that I'm going to hand
it over to Alec to take us on a
tour of Podcast Analytics.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you, Anne.
So, podcasters, every day you're
hard at work making great shows
and episodes for people to enjoy
all over the world.
But how much do you know about
your audience?
Do you know how many listeners
you have, or how much they
listen?
Do you know where they are
around the world?
What are their favorite
episodes?
With Podcast Analytics, Apple
offers you the transparency into
how you show is heard.
So, you can better understand
your listeners and create the
best show for you audience.
My name is Alec Reitter and I'm
going to do a walkthrough and
demo of Podcast Analytics.
So, let's get started by heading
to the login page.
When you see this bright purple
page, you know you've made it to
the right place.
Here, we're going to log in with
the Apple ID that we used to
originally submit the podcast
feed to the Apple Podcast
Catalog.
Now, if you have any trouble
such as, you forget your
password for your Apple ID, or
you don't know which Apple ID to
use, or if, after you've logged
in you don't see all the shows
you expect to see, go to the top
right corner of this page and
click on that question mark
icon.
That will take you to resources
and help.
And there you can find a contact
us link, where people can give
you the assistance you need.
In this example, we're going to
use John Appleseed's login
credentials.
So, let's log in now and see
what he sees when he enters
Podcast Analytics.
So, this is the shows page.
Here we see five shows for
John's account.
In this table, there are three
metrics.
And we're going to take a look
at those in a minute.
And all of the data in this
table is driven by the date
picker, which is in the top
right corner.
Right now, it's set to the last
60 days and that is the default.
So, let's take a look at the top
row for "The Very Hungry
Tourists."
Here we can see the number of
unique devices for the last 60
days.
This answers the question, how
many listeners do I have?
Here we see, 256,000 unique
devices.
Next to that, we can answer the
question how much do they
listen.
In this case, the total time
listened is 327,000 total hours.
Now, if we do a little math we
can find the average which is
the time per device of 1 hour
and 17 minutes.
So, this is a very popular show.
It's doing really well.
So, next we're going to switch
tabs from the shows tab to the
episodes tab.
Here we can see a cross-section
of episodes across all of the
shows in John's account.
Here we see a few of the most
recently released episodes.
Now, this data table has a lot
more information in it.
And let's take a look at the top
row.
This is the most recent episode
from "The Very Hungry Tourists"
starting on the righthand side
we can see the name of the
episode, then the name of the
show.
And now, the third column is the
episode column.
If you're making use of the new
tags, like season, episode and
episode type, they'll show up
here.
Following that, we have the
release date, and then the
duration.
So, in this case, it's a
35-minute long episode.
If, when you log in, you don't
see the right number in the
duration column, it's because of
what you have in your feed.
We pull this number straight
from your feed.
So, make sure it's accurate.
Following the duration column,
we see three columns that we've
seen before, except this time,
for this episode specifically.
So, we have devices, total time
listened, and time per device.
And for the first time, we see
average consumption.
This is the last metric in the
far-right column.
Average consumption is really
great because it's really just
another way of looking at time
per device.
So, in this case, it's 28
minutes for this 35-minute long
episode.
That is 81%.
What's nice about average
consumption is it allows us to
compare episodes of differing
durations against each other, to
really get a sense of how
healthy each episode is doing.
Now, from here, let's click
through on the show title and
look at the show overview for
"The Very Hungry Tourists."
So, here's the show overview.
There's a lot going on here.
Let's start at the top.
Across the top, we have three
headline numbers.
These are the same numbers that
we saw before in the shows
table.
But now we have a mini time
series underneath these numbers
to give you a sense of how
things are doing.
Maybe you can see, just looking
at that little line if your show
is getting more or fewer
listeners over time.
Now, let's look beneath this row
and take a look at the chart on
the left here.
This is the doughnut chart of
total time listened.
So, for all of the time spent
listening to your show, were
those devices subscribed or not
subscribed?
Here, we can see that 83% of
that 328,000 total hours of
listening was done by a
subscribed device, versus 17%
not subscribed.
So, these are pretty good
numbers.
But why might these numbers be
different when you take a look
at your data?
Well, if you have a very small
podcast, one with a very
dedicated following.
You might not have too many new
listeners, but your subscribed
count might be above 90 even
95%.
Conversely, if you're doing a
lot of marketing or promotion,
or your show is growing rapidly
you're not subscribed count
might be fairly high.
Now, when somebody first starts
to listen to your show,
obviously they're not going to
be subscribed most of the time.
But once they hear what you
have, and they hit that
subscribe button, that's when
they end up in the other bucket.
Oh. Now, let's take a look at
the chart to the right.
This is the top countries by
device.
Here we can see the top five
countries for the show.
As we can see, the United States
comprises the majority of the
listening at 78%.
But what's neat about this is
that if we look at the fifth
spot, we see Brazil.
Now, what's neat about this is
that Brazil wasn't on this top
five before.
But, as Anne said earlier, this
is season two of "The Very
Hungry Tourists" and on the
first episode of this season,
they actually went down to
Brazil.
They did some marketing and
promotion, and it's starting to
pay off.
So, next, let's scroll down to
the bottom of the page.
And here we can see the 10 most
recently released episodes for
the show.
This is the same sort of data
table that we saw before for
episodes, but this time it's for
a single show.
What's nice about this is we can
compare apples to apples and
really see on an
episode-by-episode basis how
things are turning out.
Let's go back up to the top, and
we're going to switch from the
show overview tab to the trends
tab.
So, here we are in the trends
This is a time series chart,
where we can see day by day how
many people are turning into the
show.
And again, by default, we're
looking at the last 60 days of
data.
In the top left corner, we see
that headline number again of
256,000 unique devices.
And down below the time series
chart, we see a table with
episode titles.
We can choose up to five
separate episodes to compare
against one another in the chart
above.
So, let's first now, talk about
all of the different dropdowns
that control the chart and what
we see in it.
First up, we have a dropdown,
this is the metric that we're
going to chart.
By default we start off with
unique devices, or you can also
choose to have it render total
time listened.
To the right of that, we have
another dropdown, this is what I
call the primary filter.
By default, here we're looking
at episode as the primary
filter.
But you might want to choose
country or subscribed device.
Now, whatever you choose for
your primary filter that's going
to dictate the table beneath the
chart.
So, whatever is selected allows
you to choose multiple entries
to compare against one another.
For example, we could choose
country and we'll have countries
in that table below.
Whatever filters are not
selected from this menu, they
move over to the righthand side
of the page in their own
dropdowns.
For example, countries or
subscription state.
For each of these, you can
choose up to one filter.
Now with that, that's enough
talking through slides.
Let's look at a demo and I will
take you back to that page, but
in a hands-on fashion.
So, here we are.
We're on that same view that we
saw before of the trends page.
But now, we can see what happens
when I interact with it.
When I move my mouse cursor over
the chart, we have this nice
data legend with details about
the specific point that I'm
hovering over.
In this case I'm looking at May
18th, where 34,000 unique
devices tuned in.
I can go down the page.
I'm going to select a few
episodes to chart against each
other.
You get this nice colorful view.
And as I mouse over, I can also
again see the details of what
I'm hovering over.
In this case, I can see episode
titles and their corresponding
counts for those days.
Now I'm going to go change my
primary filter.
And I'm going to switch it from
episode to country.
So, this updates the chart once
again.
This is the same actual graph
that we saw the first time,
because now again we're looking
at all countries.
but I'm going to choose the top
five countries and compare those
against each other.
Once again, we get this colorful
chart.
But in this particular case,
because the United States
represents so much of the
listening for this show, it
makes it difficult to see the
other countries and how they
stack up against each other.
So, I'm actually going to go and
deselect the United States.
The chart adjusts, and we can
really see with more detail how
each country is doing.
And now that I can, I'm going to
show you the date picker, it's
up here on the top right corner.
By default it's set to the last
60 days.
You can switch that to weeks, or
a specific month.
But we'll leave it at that for
now.
Now, there are lots of
combinations that you can make
here.
but I'm going to move on after
this.
But I really encourage you to
take a look at your shows and
see how they're doing and really
play around with this tool.
I think it's a lot of fun to
use.
So, let's switch over to the
show episodes tab.
And in this view, we can see the
top episodes, or the all
episodes for this show, not just
the top episodes.
In this case, this show has 11
episodes total.
And now, because all episodes
are together in this view, we
have the opportunity now to
answer some other questions like
what are the most popular
episodes.
One way to answer that is by
sorting by the unique devices
column.
When I do that, I can see that
essentially season 1, episode 4,
"Barcelona.
Barbacoa that is the most
popular by unique devices.
But maybe you think that it's
actually total time listened
that should be the determinant
of popularity.
So, I'm going to sort by that
instead.
And we see that it's actually
season 2, episode 1 that takes
the top spot.
Or, for myself, I personally
really like average consumption.
So, I'm going to sort by that,
and I can see that at 89% the
trailer is actually the most
popular episode, which makes
sense because it's a short
episode.
So, now, we've actually seen all
of the show level views, now I'd
like to take you into an episode
level view.
So, I'm going to click through
on the title for the most
recently released episode.
Here's "Broken Heirloom" this
was just released on June 1st.
Front and center we see a
timeline chart.
This shows you the audience size
over the duration of the
episode.
Actually at every 5 seconds.
And when I hoover over the
chart, I can see a data legend
again with details about the
specific time in the episode,
it's total count and its
percentage of the max.
And in the top left corner, we
see this headline number for the
total number of unique devices.
Something to note about this
chart, unlike all the other
views in Podcast Analytics, this
chart is actually for all time.
Not just a specified date range.
Now, what's really nice to see
here is that in this case, most
of the people who started this
episode actually hung out for
the entire duration.
This is a really healthy-looking
episode.
Now, beneath the chart, if I
scroll down a little bit we can
see for the last 60 days the
metrics for this show, for this
episode, I should say.
This gives you a more recent
sense of how this episode is
doing, not just all-time.
And at the very bottom, we see
the top 10 countries for this
episode.
But I'm going to scroll back up
and cover two things that I
breezed past before.
There is a dropdown menu above
that all-time devices number.
And when I click on this I can
see that I can also choose
devices or total time listened.
Now by choosing either of those,
it will actually take us into a
view which is a timeseries view
just like the show trends page.
Except this time, it's tied
specifically to this episode.
And now, the part of this graph
that I like the best is actually
the ability to playback the
audio while seeing how the
audience is reacting over the
duration of the episode.
And I can do this by going down
to the bottom left corner of the
graph and hitting this play
button.
>> [Background Music] Hey,
there, hunger heads and welcome
back to another episode of "The
Very Hungry Tourists."
I'm Maria Sanchez, PhD.
>> And I'm Johnny Appleseed.
>> In today's episode we headed
to Brooklyn-based, Vinnie's
Pizzeria.
As you'll hear, even Johnny's
massive blunder couldn't get in
the way of our culinary
adventure.
>> I'm still blushing from that
one.
>> So, this is actually a very
entertaining episode, so if you
get a chance you should
definitely check it out.
But like any basic player, you
don't just have to start at the
beginning.
You can also click on the
timeline to jump ahead to any
specific spot in time.
And if you want to fine tune,
you can grab the play head and
scrub around.
So, I'm actually going to scrub
to the beginning of what looks
like an ad.
And so, just to validate my
assumptions, I'm going to move
to just before and take a
listen.
>> Five years.
You wouldn't believe it, but in
the back there's a big.
>> As the pizza goes in the
over, let's take a moment to
hear about our great sponsors.
>> [Background Music] So, your
hands and face are smothered
with tahini sauce, so what do
you do?
>> Get a paper towel?
>> Oh, too rough.
>> Tissue?
>> Too soft.
>> What about napkins?
>> That's a great idea.
>> Napkins to You is a new drone
delivery service bringing you
napkins where and whenever you
need them.
>> Simply open the app, request
a drop-off and the closest drone
is deployed to your location.
[Background noise] By typing in
the promo code, hungry, you can
have your very own napkins
delivered for just 4.99 per
month.
>> Again, that's Napkins to You.
>> So, that sounds like a really
entertaining ad, and it's too
bad that some people decided to
skip it.
But, if you actually do the math
from before the ad to the bottom
of the ad, it's only about a 14%
drop.
And it seems like it's a
temporary drop.
So, it's doing pretty well.
So, with that,
I want to switch back to a slide
and I just want to say, that
wraps up the walk-through and
demo of Podcast Analytics for
you.
And I hope that you were able to
learn some things about how this
tool works and maybe how it can
help you better understand your
audience.
And Podcast Analytics is in
beta.
And we are very interested in
your feedback.
So, if you check the submit your
feedback link in the top left
corner right next to the beta
badge, we would love to hear
what you think about Podcast
Analytics and give us your
feedback.
Thank you.
Now, let's bring it back to
Anne.
[ Applause ]
>> Thanks, Alec that was
awesome.
So, that's a walk-through of
Podcast Analytics, which again,
is available to anyone with a
podcast in our catalog.
If you haven't used it, try it
out.
We'll also be at a lab
immediately following this
session, so come find us.
And that's where we are today,
but really we've just begun.
You guys are the reason that we
did this.
And we love hearing from you.
So, keep it coming.
For example, we know that many
of you want an API, or
subscription and download data
or geographic demographics with
more specificity.
We love the suggestions.
We hear you, and we're working
on improving the product in the
future.
We are also going to be asking
for some things from you in the
future, including new
specifications around HTTPS,
pubDates, consistent GUIDs and
cover art that meets a minimum
required resolution.
So, for continued access to
analytics in the future, you
will absolutely need to have
those four things.
We're also going to be releasing
some guidelines around best
practices for audio mastering,
to give you a sense of the
ranges you should be using so
that your podcast sounds the
best it can on HomePod and
within the context of Apple
Podcast Catalog.
We'll be sharing these
requirements with you all.
We will put them in Podcast
Resources and Help so you can
refer back to them any time.
And speaking of which, last but
not least, I want to remind you
about our resources for
podcasters.
So, we have a Branding Guide for
We also have the Affiliate
Program.
And then Podcast Resources and
Help, which you might remember
from the top right corner of the
purple screen that Alec showed
you, that features the hosting
partner list that James
mentioned.
Some tutorial videos for
analytics, and of course the
ability to contact us for help
anytime.
For more information, you can
also visit this link or like I
said, come join us in the Apple
Podcast lab immediately
following the session at 10 AM.
Thanks so much.
[ Applause ]