[ Music ]
[ Applause ]
>> Hello, welcome everyone.
My name is Gaurav and today we
are going to talk about machine
learning.
Last year we launched Core ML.
And the response from
developers, from you guys, have
been tremendous.
We are just amazed by the apps
you have made.
It clearly really is phenomenal.
So let me first begin by saying
thank you.
Thank you for embracing Core ML
and we love seeing so many of
you using it and giving
intelligent features to our
users.
We are in this together.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
It is applause to the
developers.
OK, so if you recall, Core ML
gives you an easy way to
integrate an ML model in the
app.
The idea is very simple.
You get an ML model, you drag
and drop an Xcode and with just
three lines of code you can run
state of the art ML model with
millions of parameters and
billions of calculations in real
time.
That's just amazing.
And you give your users get real
time machine learning as well
privacy friendly machine
learning.
All you have to do is to drag
and drop and ML model in Xcode.
And Core ML takes care of the
rest.
I think the big question remains
is where do I get these models
from?
So last year we provided you two
options.
The first one was you could
download some of these models,
popular models, from our
website.
But more importantly we also
released Core ML Tools.
Core ML Tools allow you to tap
the work which is done by
amazing ML Community.
So the idea is again simple.
You choose your favorite
training library, create your
model in that training library,
covert it into Core ML from
there and then just integrate it
into your app.
When we released Core ML we
released with only five or six
training libraries, support for
five or six training library,
but within a year we have a
support for all the famous
training libraries out there.
We are enhancing our tools to
even allow you more
customization and we are going
to talk about more about Core ML
tools in tomorrow's session.
Another thing we did towards the
end of the year, we released to
recreate our open source machine
learning library.
We are going to talk about to
recreate in tomorrow's session.
Bu this year we want to give you
something even more.
We want to continue our journey.
We want to give you something
native, something swiftly,
something that harnesses the
power of our Xcode, something
that puts the focus on you, our
developers, something that just
demystify machine learning for
you.
Hence we are introducing Create
ML.
[ Applause ]
Our machine learning framework
in Swift.
So Create ML completes the left
had side of the equation.
The idea is you make the model
in Create ML and you run it in
Core ML.
You do complete end-to-end
machine learning in Swift, our
favorite language.
So you are not dealing with
language oddities where you are
training in one language and
then running inference in
another language.
Create ML is simple and very
powerful.
It is tailored to your app.
It leverages core Apple
technologies and you do
everything on your Mac.
So for this year we are going to
focus on three very important
use cases.
The first one is images, second
is text, and the third one is
tabular data.
These are the top use cases that
we believe will benefit you.
So you can do things like Custom
Image Classifier.
Idea is that you make your own
image classifier that can
recognize product from your
product catalog.
You can do things like text
classifier so you can make your
own sentiment analysis, topic
analysis, domain analysis.
And you can also do classical
regression and classification on
tabular data.
For example, let's just say you
want to predict the wine quality
using its chemical composition.
The possibilities are endless
and we are going to discuss them
in detail in the next 30
minutes.
However, before we do let's take
a look at common work flow.
First, let's just say you are
trying to enable an experience
in app.
Make sure that machine learning
is the right thing to do there.
So don't just blindly apply
machine learning.
Make sure machine learning is
the right thing to do there and
define a machine learning
problem.
Second collect data.
Make sure this data reflects the
real usage of your app.
So for example if you're making
a custom image classifier that
is going to be used by users on
their iPhone, so collect
pictures from your iPhone.
Collect less screenshots but
have more iPhone pictures.
Then you train your model.
Finally another important step
here is to evaluate this model.
The model evaluation is done on
a separate handout set.
If you're happy, you write out
the ML model, but let's just say
the results are not good.
You should either reclaim your
model with different parameters
or you collect more data.
Create ML actually helps you
across all four stages of this
work flow.
We have powerful in build data
injection utilities DataSource
and DataTable that we will talk
in the remainder of the
presentation.
You can actually train your
model using only one line of
code.
And the training is done
hardware optimized.
There are built-in evaluation
metrics so you don't have to
write your own precision and
recall and confusion metrics
calculation, use them.
And then finally when you're
happy just write out the model.
Now we will take a deeper look
in all three-use cases --
Images, Text, and Table of Data.
So let's start with images and
to do that I will invite Liza
Ottens, Senior Engineer in
Machine Learning team.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you Gaurav.
Since enabling image based
experiences are some of the most
powerful and interactive ones
that you can add to your apps,
today we'll take a look at how
to train custom image
classification models.
Image classification is the
problem of identifying what
label out of a set of categories
you'd like to apply to an image.
Depending on the type of
training data, you can target
domains specific use cases to
enable in your apps.
The first step is to collect
training data.
In doing so we'll take a look at
a fruit classifier and see how
you would do so.
First you would want to gather
many varied types of images that
reflect the true data that
you'll end up seeing or that
your users will and then label
them.
First you can do this as a
dictionary with the string label
corresponding to arrays of
images or what we've noticed is
many popular data sets are
organized in hierarchical
directory structures such that
the label is the name of the
folder that contains all images
within it.
There are also other data
sources such as single folders
that contain labeled file names
and in the Create ML API we've
provided conveniences to extract
these structures.
Now training is the more complex
part of the equation.
So once you have your data this
is what you'll look at next.
And what you can do is you start
training a very complex model
from scratch on your input
images.
And for this you need lots and
lots of labeled data, you need
big compute and you need a lot
of patience.
But another well-established
technique in the industry is
transfer learning.
And since Apple has lots of
experience in training complex
machine learning models, we
already have one in the
operating system that you can
take advantage of.
So what we do is we apply
transfer learning on top of this
model that already exists in the
OS and we augment it, retraining
the last few layers to your
specific data.
So you no longer need millions
of images.
You can train a good classifier
using the amount of data that
you have.
This results in faster training
times.
And for developers that we've
worked with we've seen them go
from ours of training down to
minutes for thousands of images
or for small data sets even
seconds.
This also results in much
smaller models going from
hundreds of megabytes down to
just a few megabytes for
thousands of images or even
kilobytes for small models.
The goal with Create ML is to
abstract much of this and make
it simple and easy to use.
But to prove it let's take a
look at a demo.
And there are two work flows
that we can look at.
But first to set up the problem
I've started by running an app
that's using a state of the art
image classification model
that's already in the industry.
This one though is quite large.
It's a 100 megabytes in our app
and if we run it we have some
fruits but it's not quite what I
was looking for.
I'd really like it if instead we
could classify these particular
ones.
So what we can do is we can
switch to a new playground and
import Create MLUI and walk
through how to do this using the
UI for it.
We can define a builder,
initialize it, and to enable
drag and drop training we can
show the builder in the live
view.
This brings up a prompt in the
live view to drag in images to
begin training.
And here I've set aside some
photos of fruits -- some
blueberries and other types.
And you can drag them in and
automatically an image
classifier model begins training
on the Mac.
All of this is accelerated on
the GPU on however many
categories you end up training
on.
It automatically tells you what
the accuracy is on the training
data set.
But what's more helpful is to
try this on new images that the
model hasn't seen before to
predict how it will do on real
use cases.
So I can drag in this other
folder containing unseen images
and now the model is evaluating
on these new types of fruits.
And if you scroll, you can see
what the true label is of each
type, as well what the predicted
one was by the model.
And if you're happy with this
accuracy, what you can do is you
can take the model and drag it
into your app.
I'll add it here.
And if we take a look this model
is 83 kilobytes.
That's a huge savings down from
hundreds.
[ Applause ]
So we can delete the old model
that we were using before and in
the view controller we can
initialize this new one, Fruit
Classifier, well Image
Classifier.
We can then rerun the app, bring
up the simulator, and see how it
does on some of those fruits
that we've not trained it on.
Well, different.
On the raspberry it can no
correctly predict it since we
trained the model to recognize
raspberries.
We can even see if it can
distinguish from strawberries
and it can now depending on our
data.
But there are other workflows
you can use.
Perhaps you want to do this
programmatically or perhaps you
want to automate it.
We can also walk through how to
use the API, Create ML to do so.
So now we can switch to another
playground in import Create ML.
Since we'll be using URLs we
also can import foundation.
And since on our desktop we
still have these folders of
fruits, we can say where they
are, and also say where the
testing fruits are.
And then the next step is to
actually train the model.
So we can define a model and we
can initialize an image
classifier.
And now if we take a look at
what autocomplete shows to us we
can see, we can provide training
data in the form of a dictionary
of labels to arrays of images or
we can use a data source or even
specify model training
parameters if we want to.
Let's use a data source and
we'll use label directories
since that's how our data is
organized and specify the
trainingDir Directory.
And since we're running in the
new REPL mode of Xcode
Playgrounds I just need to hit
Shift Enter and the model begins
training right away.
You can even pull up the console
and see output of one of its
extracting features and how many
iterations it's running through.
Afterwards you can also open
Quick Looks and see the name in
the model and how many instances
it's trained on.
Now we might want to evaluate on
the testing data that we've set
aside.
So what we can do is we can call
evaluation on another data
source since that folder is
organized the same way
specifying the URL the test
data.
You can hit Shift Enter and now
the model is evaluating on these
testing datasets, testing
images.
Once it's complete we can also
look at the Quick Look and see
how many examples it evaluated
on, as well as how many classes
were in that folder all together
and the accuracy.
If we're happy with that we can
write it out.
I'll grab a code snippet here.
And say that I want to write it
to the desktop with name Fruit
Classifier ML Model.
Once I do, you can see this new
model up here is on the desktop.
We can double click it and take
a look and see it's exactly the
same.
This is also 83 kilobytes.
Furthermore, we can integrate it
back into our app the same way.
Let's recap.
[ Applause ]
We saw two ways of training
image classifier models in
Create ML.
One was with the UI, which makes
it super simple to drag and drop
your training data and
evaluation data to produce an ML
Model.
The other way was with the API,
the Create ML API using Xcode
Playgrounds.
If we walk through some of this
code we can see the first thing
we had to do was import Create
ML.
The next was to specify where
our training and testing data
was and then actually begin
training the model by specifying
how our training data was laid
out.
We can then evaluate on the
testing data and finally Save ML
Model.
If you want to automate this you
can also turn these into
scripts, which is a very popular
way of saving what you've done
and rerunning it whenever.
You can then change permissions
on the file and run them like
so.
Or for other work flows you can
always use Swift Command Line
REPL.
So we've seen today how to train
image classification models
using a few different work
flows.
Put next, I'd like to pass it
off to Tao to talk about natural
language.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you Liza.
Hello everyone, my name is Tao.
I'm an Engineer Head at Apple
working on the Core ML Team.
You just saw how easy and
intuitive to train an image
classifier with just a few lines
of code.
Now, I'm going to show you the
same can be done for natural
language.
In the easiest release we're
going to support two Natural
Language Tasks -- Text
Classification and Word Tagging.
Today I'm going to focus on Text
Classification.
For details on Word Tagging
please join the Natural Language
Session that happens tomorrow.
Text Classification can be used
in a few machine learning
applications.
For example, Sentiment Analysis.
The energy of developers is
amazing!
That's a positive note.
You want your app to know it.
[ Applause ]
Spam Analysis.
If you saw this message in your
mailbox, you know it's very
likely it's a Spam.
So you want your app to know
that as well.
Topic Analysis.
The Warriors just had an amazing
comeback win.
That's a sport post.
You want your app to be able to
classify that.
So to train such a classifier,
the first thing you do is to
collect some training data.
With Create ML we support a few
different ways for you to
organize your training data.
For example, label directories.
Here you have two folders.
One named the positive, the
other one named negative.
Within each folder you have a
number of articles with just raw
text whose true label is simply
the name of the folder.
Alternatively, you can prepare
your training data using simple
CSV, where you prepare your raw
text and the truth label
separated by comma.
We also support JSON for the
training data and know that we
just talk about training data
organization and you can
actually organize your test data
in the exact same way.
Now, with your training data and
test data ready, what are the
steps involved to train such a
text classifier?
A typical work flow would look
something like this.
You start with your raw text,
you do a language identification
to figure out which language it
is in, you convert that into
tokens, and then you convert
that into some feature values
and then you can apply a machine
learning model that gives you
some predicted value that you
have to map to some desired
label.
And then you can compare that
label to your truth label and
start reiterating on it.
With Create ML though we took
away all these complexities so
that all you need to do is to
prepare raw text with the true
label and start training
immediately.
[ Applause ]
Now let me give you a concrete
example like how you can train
such a classifier and use it.
For example, we have this simple
App called Stay Positive, whose
purpose is to encourage positive
post.
If user entered "I hate traffic"
the background turns red and we
disable the post button.
[ Laughing ]
"I love driving my car at five
miles per hour just chilling in
traffic."
That's a positive post.
We encourage you to post it.
Just imagine what our Internet
would look like this with this
app running on everybody's
phone.
[ Applause ]
Now in order to do that let me
give you a live demo.
So to train such a classifier
the first thing I do is collect
some training data.
On my desktop I have a train
folder and also a test folder.
In train folder we have two
folders.
One is named positive, the other
one negative.
And there are a number of
articles in each folder and task
folder is organized in a very
similar way.
So the first thing I do is to
import Create ML.
Now I need to tell the program
where to find my training data.
For that I'm simply using a URL
capability and then I can start
training my model using the
label directories that Liza just
showed you.
Looks like the training has
started.
As you can see on the bottom
there there's some programs
report for you to check.
It looks like the training has
finished.
Now you can check some basic
performance numbers on this
model.
For example,
model.trainingmatrics, now it
shows you this model has been
trained on over 2,000 examples
and the accuracy is 100%.
But how does it perform on some
unseen data?
So I'm going to do the same to
define test data and then
evaluate that model on the test
data.
As you can see we have 77 test
examples and we are achieving
over 94% accuracy, which is very
good.
I'm sure you want to reiterate
on it if you want to see like
even higher number, but this
number is pretty good enough for
my app.
So let me just test it out.
So to save out the model what I
need to do is define a URL where
it's saving to and then write
out the model to my desktop.
It looks like that model has
been saved.
So now I need to switch back to
my app.
Just drag and drop it.
There you go.
Now I can start use it.
I will do let model equal to
TextClassifier, which should up
complete.
And then I'm going to insert
some basic inference code.
In this inference code as you
see the first like I do is using
model.prediction to get
prediction and then in order to
hook up with this simple App UI,
I just convert that it into some
double value.
Let's give it a try.
Yeah, let's try some example we
have showed you.
"I hate traffic".
Negative.
"I love driving my car at five
mile per hour just chilling in
traffic."
Positive. Let's try something
different.
That will be fun.
"Machine learning is hard,
Create ML makes it so easy."
Positive.
[ Applause ]
So that's how you train your
customized text classifier and
drag it into your app to use it.
Here's the recap.
So to train such a classifier
the first thing you would do is
to specify data.
You specify training data as
well as your test data.
And then you can create your
model on the training data to
evaluate these performance you
evaluate a model on the test
data.
Finally to use your model in
your app you simply save it out
using this right API.
To summarize, with just a few
lines of code you can train your
customized text classifier
simple intuitive.
With that, I'd like to hand back
to Gaurav who is going to talk
about tabula data.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]
>> Thank you Tau.
Besides images and texts,
another common source of data
that requires very frequently
when you're solving a machine
learning problem is tabular
data.
What I mean by tabular data I
mean the data is spread sheet
format or in a table format.
This kind of data occurs fairly
frequently.
For example, let's just you're
trying to predict house prices
using number of beds, number of
baths, or square footage,
generally the data is arranged
in a tabular format.
You want to predict the quality
of wine using its chemical
compositions.
Chances are data will be
arranged in table format.
Or something even simple where
to hop -- which bar to hop
tonight using happy hour or
price the data will be in
tabular format.
To handle the data, which is in
tabular format, we actually
introduce a new data structure,
which we call as MLDataTable.
MLDataTable is based on
[inaudible] technology that we
will discuss in detail tomorrow.
There's something interesting
about these data tables.
The rows contain the
observations, or examples.
So here house number two has
four bed, three bath, and 500K
price.
The columns contains what we
call as features.
So the beds are features, baths
are features, square feet,
etcetera, are features.
There is one spatial column that
we want to predict, in this case
price, and this feature in this
column is known as target or
response variable.
The whole idea behind tabular
data is that we want to predict
target variable as a function of
one or many of these features.
So what are the common sources
that we support?
Well, CSV, JSON, as well you can
actually have code.
So let's take a little bit more
about MLDataTable.
First you can read data simply
by using CSV.
What is more important that you
can access the column using a
subscript notation.
So all you do is house at a
price and you get an entire of
price.
You can add to column, subtract
to column, multiply to column,
divide to columns.
And the way you do it is in very
natural looking syntax.
So you just simply say house
data price divided by house data
square feet to get price per
square feet.
Behind the scenes this
calculation is done using
evaluation and through vector
operations.
You can also do some of the
other interesting things, for
example you can split data table
in training intercept as well as
you can even do a filtering.
So for example, if you're only
interested in large houses, you
can clear and indicate a
variable and filter it out.
There are a lot of operations
that data table support.
I urge you to try it out in
Xcode Playground.
They're fun.
Now once we have data in data
table you will like to do the
training on it.
Create ML supports large number
of algorithms such as Boosted
Tree, Regularized Regression,
Random Forest, etcetera.
And all of these algorithms are
represented by their class.
In order to train your model you
only have to write one line of
code.
Basically you tell what is the
target and where you are getting
the data and which is the
algorithm you are instantiating.
So in this case, let's just say
you are running Linear
Regression, or Regularized
Linear Regression, you just
actually tell it that the data
is house data and the column is
price.
If you do Boosted Tree
Regression, just replace Linear
Regression with Boosted Tree and
you're all set.
Now Random Forest like that.
Plus we also provide a high
level abstraction ML Regression
that automatically runs all
these algorithms and choose the
best one for you.
[ Applause ]
This is inline with our
philosophy that you should focus
on task.
And the task is to predict the
price.
You should not focus about
nitty-gritty details of the
algorithm.
Having said that in case you are
expert you can actually use
Booster Tree and change its
parameters also.
So a complete end-to-end would
look like this.
It follows exactly the same
pattern as image and text.
First you specify the data.
Second you just create your
model.
Third you evaluate the model.
And once you're happy you save
it all.
So table of data, image data,
and text data, they all follow
the same pattern.
So let's just take a quick
summary of what we saw in this
session.
So Create ML is our ML framework
in Swift.
It's very simple to use and it
is very powerful and it
leverages Core Apple
Technologies.
You do end to end machine
learning in Swift on your Mac.
We also discussed about our work
flow.
Once again, you start from an
experience.
What is the experience you're
trying to enable?
Then define the problem.
Then collect the data, make sure
this data is reflective of the
real world usage of your
scenario.
Then you train the model and
then finally evaluate it.
And once you are happy you just
save it out.
Create ML is in Swift and it's
available on macOS Mojave.
You can use it in Xcode
Playground, Swift Scripts, and
Swift for Apple.
So please try it out.
We would love to hear from you.
We are here to receive your
feedback and we hope that you
will love it as much as we do.
We will be in Machine Learning
Get Together as well as in Labs
so there is tomorrow there's a
Get Together.
We will be in Labs also.
So please give us your feedback.
There are also related sessions
in the WWDC App.
We have Core ML session tomorrow
morning and an ML Session
tomorrow afternoon.
Vision session on Thursday and
we have Labs on Wednesday and
Friday.
Thank you.
[ Applause ]